Inventory of the Powell Family Papers 1775-1927
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Papers of the Powell Family, 1785-1927, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Papers, 1860-1869. (Box 2-3)
    - Papers, 1863., 57 items. (Box-folder 3:4-5)
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to wife [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 17 December [18]63., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Mentions story where Yankees come into towns and arrest southerners; refers to daguerreotypes; writes a poem/prayer to God about grief he and others have experienced.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 19 December [1863]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Wishes Nina a Merry Christmas since she (Nina) will be together with her parents; family news.
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] Powell, Charlotte [County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 28 December 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
        Discusses the inclement weather; states that she had butter and tea for celebration on Christmas morning; gives price of calico as 6 dollars per yard.
    - Papers, 1864., 83 items. (Box-folder 4:1-4)
      - Rebecca [Powell], Greenwood [Depot, Albemarle County, Virginia], to mother [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 3 January [18]64., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Comments on her friends spending New Year's Eve at the President's; mentions walking to the University [of Virginia] in Charlottesville, [Virginia]; family news; refers to cotton vs. bleached cotton; discusses typhoid fever; comments on subject of religion.
      - Lettie[?], "Linden", [Prince Edward County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia?], 4 January 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Much family news; expresses hopes for an end to the [Civil] War; mentions a book "Home Influency" that deals with raising children.
      - Hattie Powell, Mill Quarter, [?], to Selina [(Lloyd)] Powell, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse], Virginia, 6 January 1864., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Mentions losing her heart to a Lieutenant Blackford; much family news.
      - [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to [Nina Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 9 January 1864., 4 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Mentions having forgotten Nina's birthday and becoming more absentminded; states that demonstrating affection ins public is not good practice; gives advice and opinion on men and courting; has put "vie dollars in gold and $25 in Virginia. Bank notes"; and discusses school teaching; much family news.
      - Hattie [Powell],[Mill Quarter?], to Mother [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 21 January 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Has been suffering from sickness similar to typhoid fever; mentions that many servants have the measles; states that the key to her watch is worn out and she cannot wind it.
      - Mother [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to [Nina Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 23 January 1864., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Offers advice about teaching; has seen [John C. Pemberton]; family news.
      - Hattie [Powell], Mill Quarter, [?], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 25 January 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Discusses her illness [typhoid fever?]; describes her Christmas diversions.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to wife [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 27 January 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Comments on how he misses having the women in his family at home; family news; discuses some aspects of the [Civil] War; mentions Robert Young Conrad.
      - Nannie [Anne Harriotte (Lloyd) Sterns], Pittsfield, [Illinois], to "sister" [Rebecca (Lloyd) P. Tabb], n.p., January 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Much family news; expresses hope that the [Civil] War will soon end; expresses grief of her Mother's death.
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] P[owell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to "daughter" [Nina Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 4 February 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Expresses concern about Hattie Powell's sickness; much family news and town gossip; mentions some of the types of food they've been eating; talks about "yanks" and their disruptiveness; mentions Robert Young Conrad.
      - R[ebecca] C. P[owell], Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 7 February [1864]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Gives Nina advice on how to terminate her engagement with [John Dupuy]; writes of the death of Hunter McGuire's sister, May; says she now has twelve scholars; news of family and friends; discusses books and mentions Robert Young Conrad.
      - H[attie] L. P[owell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Says she has been busy knitting gloves, sewing, teaching, nursing, and being sick; says she is nearly "well and fat" again; says that her hair has not started to come back yet, but that when it does, she has been told to shave it; asks who Nina's friend Lizzie is; describes people she has met; reports where troops are; discusses ways she is trying to get cotton.
      - "Sister" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to Minnie [Mary Lee Lloyd], n.p., 9 February [18]64., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Advises Minnie not to be grieved about their mother's death; some family news.
      - Article from The Sentinel entitled Address of the President to the Army, 10 February, 1864., 1 page. NwsCl. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Article in which Jefferson Davis praises the Confederate soldiers for their "devotion and self-sacrifice," and assures them of their capabilities against the declining enemy; also includes a commentary about Davis' speech, stating that the present spirit of the South has never been paralleled in history.
      - Lizzie [Stringfellow?], Forest Hill, [?], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 11 February [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Congratulates Nina on her engagement to [John J.] Dupuy; discusses their friendship; news of family and friends.
      - [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to "child" [Nina or Rebecca Powell], n.p., 14 February 1864., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:1)
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "wife" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 16 February 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Mentions a girl's death from diphtheria; refers to traveling by train; discusses blockade of the Potomac River; comments on greenbacks and their value; refers to the Yankee Congress; general Civil War news.
      - Charles L. Powell, [Sr.], Norwood, Nelson County, Virginia, to Lt. John J. Dupuy, Prince Edward County, [Virginia], 18 February 1864., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Gives consent for him to marry Nina after listing the pros and cons of the situation.
      - [Hattie L. Powell], "Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "Mother" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 18 February 1864., 2 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Much town news and family news; refers to knitting as a pastime; states that her hair has not begun to "come out yet".
      - Hattie L. Powell, "Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 19 February 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Discusses her new beau; much family and town news; refers to events of the [Civil] War and the Powhatan troop.
      - Nina [Powell], Forest Hill, [Hanover County, Virginia], to "mother" [Selina Powell], [Charlotte County, Virginia], 22 February [1864]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Says that her employer, Mrs. Stringfellow, has offered to allow her two weeks for Easter; asks permission to come home; gives detailed plans on how she could get there cheaply; says the "troop" will return before Easter; asks if her father is coming home for the holiday.
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] Powell, Charlotte [County, Virginia], to "daughter" [Nina Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 23 February 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Discusses selection of a minister; comments on her knitting for the soldiers; town gossip and family news.
      - Frank [Lloyd Powell?], Rich[mon]d, [Virginia], to "sister" [?], n.p., 23 February 1864., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Discusses sale of a draft on New York for $625.
      - Hugh H. McGuire, Lexington, Rockbridge County, Virginia, to Hattie [Powell],[Blenheim, Albemarle County, Virginia], 23 February 1864., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Thanks her for gloves she knitted and set to him.
      - Lettie[?], "Linden", [Prince Edward County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 23 February 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Comments on her sister's problem with inflammatory rheumatism; much town and family news; tells stories of soldiers who have returned home; comments on lack of patriotism in the country; mentions readying.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, Greenwood Depot, to Nina [Powell], n.p., 23 February 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Tells of a shopping trip she took to Charlottesville, and the people she saw; describes a visit to see their father at Cousin R. Nowland's; discusses the new tax law, the "panic," and the new monetary issue; news of friends and family; mentions reading.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], 28 February [1864]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:1)
        Makes reference to needing a straw-splitter; discusses financial situation; comments on Nina's engagement to "Brother John" [Dupuy?].
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "wife" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 5 March 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Mentions interruption of communications due to Yankee Raid; states that he sat near Gen. [Robert E.] Lee and Mr. Edmund Lee on a train car and talked with them; describes conversation; discusses the events of the [Civil] War[including Lee's near capture by Custis' divisionary raid through Albemarle County, during the Kilpatrick - Dahlgren Raid on Richmond]; mentions Holmes Conrad.
      - Rebecca [Powell], Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia], 9 March 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much town news; discusses Yankees and their progression; comments on her attempts to hide her silver on her body in order to keep it from the Yankees.
      - "Mother" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to "daughter" [Nina Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 13 March 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much family news; expresses religious views.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia] to "wife" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 20 March 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much family news; discusses events of the [Civil] War; including raid by Custis on Albemarle; mentions Homes Conrad.
      - Hattie L. [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "Mother" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 21 March 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] Powell, Charlotte [County, Virginia], to "daughter" [Nina Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 24 March 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Discusses the weather; much town and family news.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County, Virginia?], 25 March [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Says her Easter plans have been cancelled because of the snow storm; mentions how close she (Nina) has been to the Yankees; says she feels much better and now weights 114 pounds; reports on fatal measles in the area; reports on how she has spent her time with Captain Morgan.
      - H[attie] L. P[owell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 31 March [1864]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Sends her a letter from Kate[?].
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] Powell, Charlotte [County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell, Hanover County, Virginia], 2 April 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Discusses buying and selling cotton; comments on college opportunities; family news.
      - R[ebecca] C. Powell, Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Hanover County?, Virginia], 6 April [18]64., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much family news and town gossip; comments on gold lace on the coats of those who make rank of Captain.
      - Fannie Mac [or Mae?], n.p., to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 11 April 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much family news; refers to Nina's grandmother's [Anne Harriotte (Lee) Lloyd] death; discusses Yankees and their progress; mentions Robert Young Conrad.
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] P[owell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 15 April 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Comments on reading as a pastime and mentions [?] Cooper's novels; much family news; refers to Yankees taking hostages; mentions Robert Young Conrad.
      - Rebecca [C. Powell], Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle, County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 19 April [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Describes her daily schedule; reports how their Aunt Jeanie Lloyd and Aunt [Re]Bec[ca] are doing in relation to the war; describes social visits; mentions an Aunt Nannie; news of family and friends.
      - S[elina] P[owell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to "daughter" [Nina Powell, Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 3 May 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Discusses weather and its effects on gardens and crops; comments on Yankees and news about the [Civil] War; much family news.
      - Rebecca [Powell], Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 5 May [18]64., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much family news; comments on news of the [Civil] War.
      - [Rebecca Powell] [?], "Forest Hill", [Hanover County, Virginia] [?], to "sister" [either Nina or Hattie Powell], n.p., 13 May 1864., 4 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Gives detailed description of fighting near Beaver Dam, [Virginia], as told to her by some of the soldiers; mentions visit by Gen. Stuart; describes other events of the war from personal point of view.
      - Rebecca [Powell], Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 17 May [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Much family news; discusses struggle on the Rapidan [River]; tells of other [Civil] War news.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 19 May 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Discusses general battle news; expresses concern about struggle in Hanover County, Virginia.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Forest Hill", [Hanover County, Virginia], to [Nina Powell, Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia] [?], 20 May 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Discusses events of the war; comments on actions of Yankees.
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] P[owell],[Charlotte County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 24 May 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:2)
        Comments on armies being at Hanover Junction and expresses her concern and fears; refers to burning of Powhatan depot by Yankees.
        Including AN from [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], to Nina Powell, [Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 24 May, 1864, correcting some spelling errors. 1 page.
      - "Mother" S[elina] P[owell], Charlotte, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Taylorsville, Hanover County, Virginia], 5 June 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Expresses relief that the Yankees did not come through the area where Nina is; says that her father wants her [Nina] to leave soon because of the danger; says things are so scarce in Charlotte that there would not be enough to feed her; expresses relief that Nina is not living between the two railroads; says the news they get about the war is encouraging, but she thinks the conflict will be a long one; discusses plans to get the family together.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Ivy Depot, [Albemarle County, Virginia], to "wife" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 6 June 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Refers to battle of Vicksburg; tells of other developments of the [Civil] War.
      - Emily [Powell], Richmond, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 24 June 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Refers to a cousin, Mrs. Randolph Tucker whose house is at the corner of Grace and Adams street in Richmond; much family news.
      - "Mother [Selina Powell], n.p. to Nina L. Powell, Belvidere, [?], [October 1863 - June 1864?]., 2 pages. AL. Incomplete, first part missing. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Asks about Nina's daily schedule and when she says prayers; expresses sorrow that Hattie's teaching position near Nina did not work out; tells her she must be self-reliant; says she is waiting to find out if she can join Mr. Powell; discusses the fashions of hats; sends her respects to Mr. Stringfellow.
      - Lizzie [Stringfellow],"Forest Hill", [Hanover County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 13 July [18]64., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
      - Lizzie [?], Petersburg, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[care of James M. Booker, Moores Ordinary, Prince Edward County, Virginia], 23 July [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Describes her social schedule; encourages her to pursue a relationship with Willie Booker; news of family.
      - "Uncle Edmund" [?], Danville, Virginia, to Re[becca Powell],[Greenwood Depot, Albemarle County, Virginia], 26 August 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Recounts all he has been doing for the past two years (has been in charge of a prison.
      - C. Stringfellow, [Hanover County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 4 September [1864?]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Asks Nina to change her mind and work for them another year; claims they are safe from the Yankees and that the war will soon be over; praises her teaching of their three girls.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, "Kenmuir," [Louisa County, Virginia], to "Mother" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 18 September [18]64., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Discusses Yankees' burning of houses in Richmond; gives views on death; much family news.
      - C[harles] L. Powell, [Sr.], Madison River Station, [?], to "wife" [Selina (Lloyd) Powell, Charlotte County, Virginia], 18 September 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Comments on typhoid fever; family news.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, "Kenmuir," [Louisa County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia], 21 September [18]64., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Much Family news. mentions not being able to find a nail-brush in the city and forgot india ribbon; comments on Yankees treating people badly; refers to buying lip-glue at Randolph's Book Store; discusses her, Nina's, new house.
      - S[elina] P[owell], Mr. Redd's, [?], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 24 September [1864]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Describes Mr. Powell's teaching position with the Scott family; says he is trying to find a place near him for her to stay; says there was a Yankee raid near where he is staying; discusses where friends who are soldiers are stationed; mentions families who are looking for wounded soldiers to employ as teachers.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Richmond, Virginia], 29 September 1864., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Much family and town news.
      - Lettie[?], Linden, [Prince Edward County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Richmond, Virginia], 29 September 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Comments on symptoms of the "fever"; expresses religious beliefs concerning deaths resulting from battles; much family news and town news.
      - S[elina (Lloyd)] P[owell], Charlotte C[our]t House, [Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 7 October [1864] [?]., 4 pages. Incomplete. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Much family news; discusses teacher's pay.
      - [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse], Virginia], to Nina [Powell], Richmond, [Virginia], 10 October [1864?]., 4 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Much family and town news; inquires about her new home in Richmond, Virginia.
      - Hattie L. Powell, "Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 13 October [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Discusses one of Nina's pupils and how Nina should act towards the family that is employing her; mentions arrangements to exchange a pair of shoes; reports on friends and family; reports on "her Willie," and where he is stationed; mentions soldiers for whom she has knitted gloves.
      - R[ebecca] C. P[owell], Greenwood [Depot],[Albemarle County, Virginia], to "Father" [Charles L. Powell, Sr.], n.p., 17 October [1864]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Discusses the suitability of Mr. Starke's teaching offer for her mother.
      - "Sister" Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to [Nina Powell], [Richmond, Virginia], 24 October [1864]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Chides Nina for not writing her; asks if she is spending all her time with Willie Dupuy] who has a wounded shoulder; reports on what she has done socially; asks her to get some cartridges for her pistol when she buys some for her own gun; says Minna Booker is to be married November fourth; discusses sewing.
      - [Selina (Lloyd) Powell], Charlotte [County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Richmond, Virginia], 26 October 1864., 2 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Complains about difficulties in the teaching profession; family news.
      - Rebecca C. Powell, Greenwood Depot, [Albemarle, County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 27 October [1864?]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Describes her situation at the Garrett's, teaching Lizzie and others; emphasizes the importance of letter writing now that they are apart; discusses Mr. Irving's[?] failing health; says Lizzie has diphtheria; describes social events; discusses Nina's problems with teaching Blanche; reports on friends who have been wounded or killed in the war; asks bout Cousin Mary Lee and Cousin Emily.
      - Lizzie [Stringfellow],[Verdon, Hanover County, Virginia, to Nina Powell, [care of Dr. James Powell, Richmond, Virginia], 27 October [1864?]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Reports that her brother Rob has been wounded and may have to have his leg amputated; says her brother Jimmie is in Charleston where there is much yellow fever; says they work all day without rest; more family news.
      - Hattie [Powell],"Blenheim", [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell], n.p., 31 October [1864?]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Gives advice on how Nina should manage one of her pupils; reports on what she is doing; discusses clothes; mentions Minna's wedding.
      - Lettie [?], Linden, [Prince Edward County, Virginia], to Nina [Powell],[Richmond, Virginia], 2 November 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)